<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on New Light</title>
    <link>https://azure562.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on New Light</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2023-{year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 13:23:32 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://azure562.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A brief discussion: Copywriting, Technical writing, UX writing, and product experience</title>
      <link>https://azure562.github.io/blog/copy-tech-ux-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 13:23:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure562.github.io/blog/copy-tech-ux-writing/</guid>
      <description>Photo by fauxels from Pexels
Have you ever wondered about the various types of writings, or what exactly that guy/gal with a title of “some writer” is doing?
Traditionally in the job market there are two categories of writing positions: copywriting and technical writing. Not long ago there entered a new one: UX writing. But what’s the difference? And what is the implication to the profession of writing and to the business world in general?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write (and I know you know) - Part I</title>
      <link>https://azure562.github.io/blog/how-to-write-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 20:38:56 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure562.github.io/blog/how-to-write-1/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Ketut Subiyanto from Pexels
If you have established your credibility as a technical writer or communicator, it’s only natural that people come to you for advice on writing.
Though almost every profession has to deal with some writing tasks, most of the time a well-defined template could guarantee a decent output.
Chances are, those who come to you are not asking for a template. If they are not committed to becoming a tech writer, what advice would you give, advice that is generic enough while still focus on technical aspects (a knowledge-sharing topic, a how-to guide, or a draft for a section in tech docs)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lean Writer</title>
      <link>https://azure562.github.io/blog/lean-writer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 19:58:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure562.github.io/blog/lean-writer/</guid>
      <description>How does a tech writer create value in the customer-centric era?
Photo by Jessica Lynn Lewis on Pexels
Still optimizing for editorial skill? Though the job title of Tech Writer is nothing new, the scope of a tech writer’s work is never clear-cut.
Traditionally, tech writers are responsible for:
editing the drafts provided by developers applying some editorial styles publishing the final user documentation Such a perspective puts tech writers at the downstream of product development and leads to the practice of allocating one tech writer to multiple projects (often across different products).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Information</title>
      <link>https://azure562.github.io/blog/reference-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 20:01:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://azure562.github.io/blog/reference-info/</guid>
      <description>Here are some resources that I find useful.
Style The Chicago Manual of Style
Microsoft Writing Style Guide
Writing Course Google Technical Writing Course
Wikiversity Technical Writing course: free writing courses, two levels: level 1 and leve-2
Blog I&amp;rsquo;d rather be writing
Technical Writer
Content Marketing Content Marketing Institute Content Management/Stategy The Content Wrangler Developer Experience Developer Portals: Pronovix hosts a yearly DevPortal Awards and a conference series API The Docs conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
